

#### SOFTWARE + DATA

★ Stockholm, Sweden | ■ igor@fer.st | % igor.fer.st | ♠ igorferst | ★ i

## Summary.

I'm an experienced engineer who loves helping data scientists and analysts extract insights from complex, large-scale data. I've spent my career supporting technical data needs across a variety of domains (insurance, healthcare, capital markets, and others) as both a data engineer and software engineer.

I have deep experience across the entire data stack: designing and building pipelines, ETL, data modeling, and executing analytics/data science projects. I focus on aligning technical work with business needs, and enjoy engaging directly with data users around requirement gathering and validation, training and upskilling, etc.

## Work Experience

## **Bridgestone Mobility Solutions**

Stockholm, Sweden

SR. DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING/DATA ENGINEERING LEAD

Feb. 2021 - present

My startup Mobikit was acquired and its product incorporated into Bridgestone's software portfolio as a data-driven fleet risk management product for insurance carriers and fleet owners. I continue to lead data engineering and product development.

- Oversee the design and implementation of our telematics data pipeline, with a focus on scalability, reliability, and observability.
- Manage globally distributed team of data and product engineers: hiring, onboarding, coaching, optimizing processes.
- Manage personnel and cloud budgets, set technical priorities.
- Own and execute high-value customer implementations.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2/Kinesis/Glue, Docker

Mobikit Columbus (OH), USA

**CO-FOUNDER/CTO**Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2021

Technical co-founder of a startup building a data analytics platform for large-scale vehicle telematics data. I oversaw data

engineering, product development, and customer implementation.

- Architected and led development of data pipeline to ingest, harmonize, and enrich telematics data from heterogenous sources.
- Defined and validated data model with current and prospective customers.
- Oversaw design and development of platform's analytics features and executed ad-hoc analytics and data science projects.
- Contributed code across the entire stack, from data pipeline to ETL to application backend to UI.
- Implemented data security and data governance features to meet enterprise requirements.
- Raised funding, guided company to product-market fit, and exited successfully.
- Grew and managed globally distributed team of developers.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2, Docker, Javascript(React)

Root Insurance Columbus (OH), USA

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/DATA ENGINEER

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Worked at a growth-stage insuretech unicorn on various data-intensive projects.

- Prototyped a machine-learning model to enhance insurance rate accuracy.
- Implemented support for new rating methodologies and executed historical backtests for rating changes.
- Python SME for engineering and actuarial teams.
- Technologies include: Ruby (Rails), Python (scikit-learn), Ansible

Enlace Health Columbus (OH), USA

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2018

Enlace is a healthtech company building large-scale data analytics tools to support innovative models of healthcare delivery. I joined as an early employee working on the analytics platform, and was then asked to lead a team building a new product.

- Designed novel graph algorithm as part of PySpark ETL pipeline for health claims data.
- Led a cross-functional team building a care management and revenue cycle management product for surgical centers.
- Owned product design and technical architecture, maintained product roadmap, implemented features.
- Introduced and trained engineering team on new technologies (Docker, Angular), development processes (TDD, code reviews), and agile methodology (user stories, estimation).
- Technologies include: Python (Flask, PySpark), Javascript (Angular, Node.js), SQL (PostgreSQL, Redshift), Docker

JUNE 20, 2023 IGOR FERST

InSample San Francisco (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2014

First employee at a healthcare analytics startup building a cloud-based tool for statistical de-biasing of clinical experiments.

- Designed and built the product protoype together with the CTO.
- Prepared fundraising materials and interviewed prospective customers.

Google Mountain View (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2014

Part of the conversion tracking team building tools that Google's customers use to understand the effectiveness of their ad spend.

- Implemented a novel conversion tracking visualization for the AdWords suite of analytics tools.
- · Developed enhancements to Google Analytics machine-learning algorithm for attribution modeling.

I worked on Palantir Metropolis, a data integration and quantitative research platform for capital markets.

## **Palantir Technologies**

Palo Alto (CA), USA

FORWARD DEPLOYED ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2013

- Embedded with the platform's largest customer, a prominent global macro hedge fund.
- Product owner and developer for platform's visualization and reporting features.
- Trained users in data analysis tools and gathered product requirements.

## Skills\_

**General** Data engineering, software engineering, product management, data science, technical leadership

**Languages** Python (primary), SQL, Javascript, Ruby, Java

**Frameworks** Django/DRF, Pandas, React, Rails

Infrastructure AWS (RDS, EC2, Cloudformation, serverless, Kinesis, and more), Docker, PostgreSQL, Github

**Technical Expertise** Statistics, optimization, machine learning, data modeling, graph algorithms

## Education

Cornell University Ithaca (NY), USA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- PhD candidate in Applied Mathematics supported by a US National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship.
- Published original research in algorithms and optimization: https://tinyurl.com/ycheu4us

### **University of Waterloo**

Waterloo (Ontario), Canada

M.MATH. IN COMBINATORICS & OPTIMIZATION

### **University of Chicago**

Chicago (IL), USA

**B.S. IN MATHEMATICS WITH HONORS** 

# **Volunteering**

Odesa Peace Fund Stockholm, Sweden

• General IT guidance and support for a US-based nonprofit providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine.

Hack OHI/O Columbus (OH), USA

• Twice served as judge and mentor for Ohio State University's student hackathon.

### United Schools Network Columbus (OH), USA

• Designed and taught a three month after-school programming course for middle-school students.

• Developed spreadsheet-based operational tools for school administrators.

### Columbus Arts Festival Columbus (OH), USA

- Member of organizing committee for 2016 and 2017 festivals.
- Built mobile-friendly web-based interactive festival map.

June 20, 2023 | Igor Ferst 2